theayurvedaexperience.com 2015-05-24

# Privacy Policy - The Ayurveda Experience

## We All Need Privacy. Here’s Our Commitment To Yours

### Brief of Our Privacy Policy

For those who want the short and relevant answer, we will always, ALWAYS, respect your privacy, your email address, and the information you give us. We’re not going to sell it, trade it, or abuse any information you submit to us. But I’m sure you’ve got some questions. Here’s our answers to what may be running through your mind.

#### 1\. How’s my information going to be used?

When you sign up you’ll only get relevant information about The Ayurveda Experience, Personal Development, complimentary access to The Ayurveda Experience Method Starter Kit and programs, products or complimentary online events that pertain to Personal Growth, Meditation or Spirituality.

For full disclosure on how your information is used, head here »

#### 2\. How do I to stop receiving emails from you in the future?

If you wish to stop receiving emails from us, you may unsubscribe at any time using the link provided at the bottom of all our emails. But if you’re still receiving emails from us, don’t worry, our Customer Support Team will be there to assist you!

All you have to do is drop our Customer Support an email at lissa@theayurvedaexperience.com

#### 3\. Who’s going to get my information?

Your information’s safe with us. So don’t worry about getting spam emails about any unrelated subjected to the matters we have mentioned above. These emails will always be sent from us and only us. We’ll never give out your email address or any of the information you submit on this site to anyone else.

For full disclosure on how your information is used, head here »

#### 4\. What if I email you guys?

Your emails are confidential, we won’t share your email, data, or email address. Cool? It’s just between you and us.

More on email privacy here »

#### 5\. Do you guys use cookies?

Yes we do use cookies, but our cookies don’t contain any personal information. We use them to help you make using our website easier, such as:

  * to remember your country and language preferences
  * to deliver information that match your interests
  * to help us understand our audience and traffic patterns
  * to let you automatically log into programs and parts of our site that require membership
  * to manage and present site info displayed on our website that will be specific to you

More on cookie usage here »

We also use Web Beacons to collect non-personal data on how you use our site, such as how long did you visit our page, what web browser you’re using, what’s your operating system, and who’s your Internet service provider. This data is collected from thousands of site visits and analyzed as a whole. This helps us build a better website to match your needs.

But if any of this feels uncomfortable to you, head here to disable cookies and beacons on your computer »

#### 6\. What if I post in one of your forums or blog posts?

Occasionally we hold public discussions through forums within our site. This may be on blog posts we put up or in our membership area. Please be aware that this is public space. Would you shout out your credit card information in public? Probably not. Use this same discretion when you post in our forums and when commenting.

Learn more about our forums here »

#### 7\. How tech savvy are you guys when it comes to data security?

We’re _real_ good. We have a ton (and wide variety, may I mention) of administrative, managerial, and technical security measures put in place to protect your personal information. We’ve never had a breach of security and always strive for excellence in maintaining your privacy.

It is mandatory for our tech team to wear these nerd glasses. This ensures 100% tech savviness so that you’re data is always safe.

For more on data security, click here »

Got more questions? You can get a hold of our customer happiness manager at lissa@theayurvedaexperience.com  
For the full and ever so much fun legalese, just read below 

## Your privacy is very important to us.

### We want to make your experience on the Internet as enjoyable and rewarding as possible, and we want you to use the Internet’s vast array of information, tools, and opportunities with complete confidence.

We have created this Privacy Policy to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy and security. This Privacy Policy describes how our company collects information from all end users of our Internet services (the “Services”), including those who access some of our Services but do not have accounts (“Visitors”) and those who may purchase Products and/or pay a monthly service fee to subscribe to the Service (“Members”). This Policy also explains what we do with the information we collect, and the choices Visitors and Members have concerning the collection and use of such information. We request that you read this Privacy Policy carefully.

## Personal information our company collects and how it is used.

### Introduction

Members may be asked to provide certain personal information when they sign up for our Products or Services including name, address, telephone number, billing information (such as a credit card number), and the type of personal computer being used to access the Services. The personal information collected from Members during the registration process (or at any other time) is used primarily to provide a customized experience as you use our Products and Services. Your information will never be licensed or sold to any third party. However, we may make limited disclosure of personal information under the specific circumstances described in the “Disclosure” section below.

### Affiliate Links

Occasionally you may have clicked on one of Ayurveda Experience affiliate links and signed up or bought something via that link. In this case, the person or organization in charge of the affiliate link will have the information that you have submitted. This may be your email address, name, address, or whatever else they asked you. If you have signed up for bought something from Ayurveda Experience via an affiliate link, please check the privacy policy on their site.

### Online shopping

If you order services or products directly from our Company we will use the personal information you provide only to process that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order.

If you complete an order for some other company(ies) that may be linked to our Site, such as an online gift order sent directly to a recipient, you may be asked to provide information about the recipient, such as the recipient’s name, address, and phone number. Our company has no control over the third parties’ use of any personal information you provide when placing such an order. Please exercise care when doing so. We recommend that you familiarize yourself with the Privacy and Terms of Use policies of any other company(ies) whose web sites you may access from our site.

### Responses to email inquiries

When Visitors or Members send email inquiries to our company, the return email address is used to answer the email inquiry we receive. Our company does not use the return email address for any other purpose and does not share the return email address with any third party.

Thanks for reading our privacy policy.

### automatic collection of information

 **Cookies:** Our Company may use “Cookies” to collect information. Cookies are small pieces of information stored by your browser on your computer’s hard drive, at a web site’s request. Our Company Cookies do not contain any personal information, but are used primarily as follows:

  * to keep track of temporary information. For example, Cookies allow us to keep track of the pictures you upload and download;
  * to register you in special programs. Cookies allow us to remember you when you login to the places on our site that require Membership;
  * to remember your country and language preferences;
  * to help us understand the size of our audience and traffic patterns;
  * to collect and record information about what you viewed on our Web site and what you viewed in our e-mail;
  * to manage and present site information and the pictures displayed on your computer, and
  * to deliver information specific to your interests.

web beacons: We may also place small “tracker gifs” or “beacons” on many of the pages on our website, in online advertising with third parties, and in our email. We use these beacons, in connection with Cookies, to collect non-personal data on the usage of our site including but not limited to the date and time of the visit, the pages visited, the referring web page, the type of browser (e.g., Internet Explorer, NetScape), the type of operating system (e.g., Windows, Linux, or Mac), and the domain name of the visitor’s Internet service provider (e.g., <span class=;”>AOL). This information is collected about thousands of site visits and analyzed as a whole. This information is useful in, for example, tracking the performance of our online advertising such as online banner ads and to determine where to place future advertising on other web sites.

 **Disabling Cookies and Beacons** : If you are uncomfortable with the collection of such information through the use of Cookies and Beacons, we recommend disabling these features through your browser preferences, though please understand this will limit the performance and functionality of our Company’s Web site. Your browser documentation should provide specific procedures for disabling cookie and beacon support.

### Public forums

Some parts of our site may enable you to participate in public services such as discussion boards, chats, and live events. Please use discretion when posting personal information about yourself when using these services. Be aware that when you disclose personal information at these sites, such as your name, member name, email address, etc., the information may be collected and used by others to send unsolicited email. The services are open to the public, and what you post there can be seen by anyone and is not protected. We try to moderate the comments as best we can but we can’t guarantee total control of the comments that you may receive while you participate in these services. Sometimes, you may find other people’s comments to be offensive, harmful or inaccurate.

### Our company’s commitment to data security

We implement a variety of administrative, managerial, and technical security measures to help protect your personal information. Our Company has various internal control standards which relate specifically to the handling of personal information. These include certain controls to help safeguard the information we collect online. Our employees are trained to understand and comply with these controls and we communicate our Privacy Notice, practices and guidelines to our employees. However, while we strive to protect your personal information, you must also take steps to protect your information. We urge you to take every precaution to protect your personal information while you are on the Internet.

Services and Web sites we sponsor have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. While we make every effort to ensure the integrity and security of our network and systems, we cannot guarantee that our security measures will prevent third-party “hackers” from illegally obtaining this information.

### Revisions to this policy

Our Company reserves the right to revise, amend, or modify this policy, our Terms Of Use & Service agreement, and our other policies and agreements at any time and in any manner, by updating this posting.

## Where to direct questions about our privacy policy…

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the practices described herein, you may contact us at lissa@theayurvedaexperience.com or at alicia@theayurvedaexperience.com

Thanks so much for reading this thing.
